Talent wins races. Courage creates champions.
Heart of Champions is a drama film directed by Michael Mailer.
During their last year at an Ivy League college in 1999, a group of friends and crew teammates' lives are
changed forever when an army vet takes over as coach of their dysfunctional rowing team.
Jack Murphy, played by Michael Shannon.
Alex, played by Alexander Ludwig.
Chris, played by Charles Melton.
John, played by Alex MacNicoll.
MJ, played by Andrew Creer.
Nisha, played by Ash Santos.
Heart of Champions (also known as Pressure Point in Australia and the United Kingdom, and Swing in Germany, also its working
title) is a 2021 American sports drama film directed by Michael Mailer, from a screenplay by Vojin Gjaja.
It stars Michael Shannon, Alexander Ludwig, Charles
Melton, David James Elliott and Ash Santos.
The film was released on October 29, 2021 by Vertical Entertainment.
The film follows the rowing team of a fictional Ivy League university as they aim to win the
national championship under the tutelage of a new coach, a Vietnam veteran.
The film explores themes of affectation, calm,
candid, cautionary, inspirational.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.